Jordan Khalil

JavaScript Developer

jordankhalil0@gmail.com | (586) 918-1296 | Macomb, MI | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SUMMARY

A certified software developer motivated to expand and grow from new opportunities in the I.T. sector. 3+ years of experience in client advocacy roles which has built strengths in computer troubleshooting, client relations, and client satisfaction. Driven to find a better way while being obsessed with client satisfaction. Project-focused while being mendable to team cohesion.

EDUCATION

Grand Circus Coding Bootcamp

September 2022 – December 2022

Full Stack Javascript Certificate

Celestial Typer [Typescript, MERN, API]

• Developed a full-stack application using MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js. Sourced a third-party API to show current NASA articles and created an interactive typing game that allows the user to practice their typing skills.

Recipe Website [Javascript, React, API]

• Built a recipe website that integrated typescript, React, and API that used built-in fetch function Axios, tested dependencies, and applied React Routers, and Wireframes with Figma.

<u>Card Match Game</u> [Javascript, Document Object Models, CSS, HTML]

• Built a card-matching game website with Javascript, that implemented Document Object Models to control the functionality of the game and demonstrated knowledge in CSS and HTML.

Macomb Community College, Warren, MI

May 2022

Associate Business Administration

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavascriptMongoDBObject Oriented ProgrammingData StructuresTypescriptExpressDocument Object ModelGit BashHTMLReactFull-Stack DevelopmentTest Driven-DevelopmeCSSNode.JSSQLContinuous Integration
--

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Rocket Mortgage, Detroit, MI

Executive Client Advocate

June 2021 - June 2022

- Received 3,000 inbound phone calls monthly to help clients throughout the loan origination process.
- Entrusted to de-escalate 15 high-profile clients per day to increase the company quality assurance bottom line.
- Received 40 inbound phone calls per day to resolve client-facing technology issues.

Senior Closing Care Specialist

July 2020 - 2021

- Scheduled 10 mortgage closing dates per day, yielding over \$800,000 weekly in revenue.
- Recognized by leadership for the highest success rate of 88% by recovering clients that were at risk of loan withdrawal.

Gamestop, Utica, MI

Senior Guest Advisor

November 2018 – July 2020

- Drove substantial sales with more than \$1500 weekly revenue through suggestive selling and promoting add-on purchases.
- Surpassed daily sales goals by 15% by cross-selling and promoting additional products.